ABOUT ME

My name is Kevin Snijders, 26 years old, a hard-working and stress-resistant graduate student as a software engineer at the Hogeschool van Amsterdam. During my study, I enjoyed the knowledge that I gained which was heavily focused on the backend. Through experiences such as internships and a parttime job as a Front-end Developer, I found out that I was interested in Frontend as well (maybe even more than backend). As a result, I am now focusing on finding a job as a Junior Front-end Developer, but perhaps in the future, I want to be able to combine them and go for Fullstack Developer.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's degree, Software engineering. Hogeschool van Amsterdam (Amsterdam)

2014 - 2018.

Applicatioentwikkelaar (MBO 4). Horizon college (Purmerend)

• 2010 - 2014

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sofa Superstars (graduate internship)

2017 - 2018

Function: Full-stack Developer

Description: Sofa Superstars wanted to boost the engagement with its users with the functionality to be able to send near-real-time notifications to different (groups of) users. My task was, therefore, to develop a Cross-site messaging system with near-real-time delivery.

Activities:

- A thesis with research into the various options that could be used for this use case.
- Developing a backend system based on Django, Django Channels and Python.
- Creating API's
- Implementing the use of WebSockets.
- A React library component with Rollup. JS to being able to reuse implement in the various websites.

Sofa Superstars (parttime job)

2016 - 2017

Function: Front-end developer

Description: After I had completed my internship at Sofa Superstars, I was offered a parttime job as a Front-end developer.

Activities:

- Developing React components or features.
- Refactoring parts of the older codebase.
- Convert PSD designs (from zeplin.io) to HTML templates.
- A point of contact for a Frontend intern.
- Providing support on new and old projects.

Sofa Superstars (internship)

2015 - 2016

Function: web developer

Description: During my second study year, I opted for a web development internship because I wanted to know more about that. Since I had little experience in the field, I initially focused on smaller tasks to become familiar with, for example, Sass, React, tools for task managers such as Gulp, and more. At the end of the internship, I fully participated in the development team.

Activities:

- Developing React components or features
- Converting parts of Vanilla JavaScript to React.
- Working on the responsiveness of various websites.

The development of FC Groningen Rapport from scratch

Youngbits (Internship) 2013 – 2014

Function: Web developer

Description: During this internship, I have been working on learning the basics of web development, a bit about web design and editing.

Activities:

- Convert PSD to HTML templates.
- Modifying existing websites (HTML, JavaScript, jQuery, and CSS).
- The development of simple (WordPress) websites.
- Learning the basics of Photoshop by designing webpages.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

Personal website – Front-end Developer (2019 – 2019): Since I did not have a personal website to show my portfolio, I developed it. The website is split into a client project (Front-end) where the latest technologies are being used, such as React, Webpack, Flexbox and more. Github pages is used to host the Front-end (see also https://kevinsnijders.github.io/). For the Back-end a simple Express server was created with a Postgres database in which the projects and technologies are stored. The hosting of the backend is done by Heroku.

KLM workshop tool – Co-Developer (2014 – 2015): The assignment was to develop an interactive tool that could be used while giving workshops. Before if the client gave a workshop everything was done with printed forms. The codebase of the project is built with Java Spring / Hibernate, AngularJS, Bootstrap, HTML & MySQL.

KNOWLEDGE

HTML5, Sass, Bootstrap, JavaScript, React, Jest, Webpack, Gulp, Databases (MySQL en Postgres), Node.js, Python, Django, Java, Git, Jira en Scrum.

SOFT SKILLS

Trustworthy, flexibility, perseverance, teamplayer, willingness to learn, patience, and stress resistant.

REFERENCE

Upon request.